patientnotebook.com 2016-04-08

# Patient Notebook

Last Modified: Jan. 30, 2016

The privacy of your personal health and financial information is paramount. This privacy policy describes how ZirMed Inc. (variously, "ZirMed", we, our or us) protects and handles the personal information that you or your healthcare provider furnishes to ZirMed. We obtain your information through our web-based service at [https://www.patientnotebook.com](https://www.patientnotebook.com/) and related web sites ("Patient Notebook"). 

### 1\. Introduction

Patient Notebook is bringing together the latest technology and medical information to make managing your healthcare expenses and information much easier. With Patient Notebook, you can: (1) pay your medical bills quickly, easily and securely; (2) store and manage all types of healthcare communications in one central place; (3) and access other online health tools. The availability of these tools will vary based on which components of Patient Notebook your healthcare provider chooses to make available to you.

Each person's information is stored and accessed separately in his or her own Patient Notebook account. 

###  2\. Creating an Account and Records: Collection of Your Personal Information 

You choose whether or not to create an account with Patient Notebook.  Creating an account is not necessary to submit payments.  Your healthcare provider controls your ability to create a Patient Notebook account, and some providers may elect not to make this functionality available. If you do not choose to create an account, or your healthcare provider does not allow you to create one, you will only be allowed to: (a) send your healthcare provider an update to your mailing address; (b) send your healthcare provider an update to your insurance information; (c) request that your physician's office call you; (d) access limited information about current balances due to, and statements from, your provider; (e) make an online payment. Your ability to conduct these actions will be determined by which components of Patient Notebook your healthcare provider chooses to make available to you. 

The first time you sign in to Patient Notebook, you will be asked to create your username and password. To do so, you must provide personal information, such as your email address, name, and date of birth. We will use the email address you provide to send you an email requesting that you validate your account. 

You can review and update your account information. You can also modify, add, or delete any optional information by signing into your Patient Notebook account and editing your account profile.

An account allows you to manage your health and wellness bills and utilize the tools offered on Patient Notebook. Once you have an account, you can view, store, and pay health bills for yourself and dependents (to the extent you have the right to do so and if your healthcare provider has elected to make such functionality available).

When you send email or other communications to us, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests, and improve our services. 

Saving payment methods within Patient Notebook makes those credit/debit cards and checking/savings accounts available for your future use within Patient Notebook. These payment methods are available solely for use by you and any persons you grant access to your Patient Notebook accounts (to the extent such functionality is made available). Your healthcare provider cannot use the payment methods stored in Patient Notebook. Your healthcare provider may be aware of general details about the method you used to make a payment. 

### 3\. Account and Record Access and Controls

You are the custodian of any records you create or your healthcare provider sends to your account. 

###  4\. How We Use Your Personal Information 

We use personal information collected through Patient Notebook, including health and wellness information, to enable the services provided through Patient Notebook and as described in this privacy statement. We also allow your healthcare providers to download certain demographic data about you that you voluntarily supply to us. We do not use or disclose your information except as described in this privacy statement. In support of these uses, we may use personal information to: provide you with important information about Patient Notebook, including critical updates and notifications; send you email and/or mobile alerts; modify your Patient Notebook account to better address your health or financial needs; and determine appropriate services relevant to you, your lifestyle and your geographic location. 

We may access and/or disclose your personal information if we believe such action is necessary to: (a) comply with the law or legal process served on us; (b) protect and defend our rights or property (including the enforcement of our agreements); or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety and welfare of Patient Notebook users or members of the public. Personal information collected on Patient Notebook is currently stored and processed in the United States. 

We will not sell data that personally identifies you. 

###  5\. How We Use De-identified and Aggregated Information and Statistics 

We may use de-identified or aggregated information gathered from Patient Notebook and related statistics to improve the services provided through Patient Notebook, and for certain research and analysis including clinical medical research. We may also provide this information to our partners for such purposes. De-identified information does not include personally identifiable information such as name, email address, or address, but may include gender, height, weight, postal code, and medical information. Aggregated information is information from multiple users that is not associated with any individual user account. 

### 6\. Sharing Records with Testing Providers and Other Providers through Patient Notebook

Throughout Patient Notebook, you might be provided with information about other service providers or healthcare providers (such as NoMoreClipboard) that connect with Patient Notebook. You should examine these providers' individual privacy policies and terms of service prior to using their services because this privacy policy does not apply to the activities of such providers. We encourage you to contact us if you believe a provider is not protecting the privacy or security of your health and wellness information. 

With legal questions or concerns, please contact us at: [legal@patientnotebook.com](mailto:legal@patientnotebook.com). 

### 7\. Email and Mobile Alerts

To keep you informed of the latest improvements and alerts relating to your Patient Notebook account, Patient Notebook may send you emails and/or mobile alerts. You have the ability to opt out of receiving certain emails and/or mobile alerts. 

###  8\. Security of Your Personal Information 

We are committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, and disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide encrypted on computer servers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities. We restrict access to personal information to Patient Notebook employees, contractors, and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop, or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations. 

### 9\. Enforcement of This Privacy Policy

If you have questions regarding this policy, you should contact us at [legal@patientnotebook.com](mailto:legal@patientnotebook.com). 

###  10\. Use of Cookies 

We use cookies to enable you to sign in and to help personalize Patient Notebook. A cookie is a small text file that a web page server places on your hard disk. It is not possible to use cookies to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. A web server assigns cookies uniquely to you, and only a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you can read the cookies. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, if you personalize a web page, or navigate within a site, a cookie helps the site to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. Using cookies simplifies the process of delivering relevant content and eases site navigation. When you return to the web site, you can retrieve the information you previously provided, so you can easily use the site's features that you customized. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline some or all cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline all cookies, you may not be able to use interactive features of this or other web sites that depend on cookies. 

###  11\. Changes to This Privacy Statement 

We may occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also revise the "last modified" date at the top of the privacy statement. For material changes to this privacy statement, we will notify you either by placing a prominent notice on the home page of Patient Notebook or by sending you a notification directly. We encourage you to review this privacy statement periodically to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. Your continued use of Patient Notebook constitutes your agreement to this privacy statement and any updates. Please be aware that this privacy statement and any choices you make on Patient Notebook do not necessarily apply to personal information you may have provided to us in the context of other of our separately operated products or services. 

###  12\. Contact Information 

We welcome your comments regarding this privacy statement. If you have questions about this statement or believe that we have not adhered to it, please contact us by email by following this link: [legal@patientnotebook.com](mailto:legal@patientnotebook.com).

Patient Notebook is our registered trademark. NoMoreClipboard and other trademarks hereon are property of their respective owners.
